okay let's
see we do expect that people can hear us
now can people
maybe I don't know if people can give us
a yes ah there's a thumbs up from
somebody so it looks like we have
started the meeting and um I am guessing
that people can see my front screen a go
for GitHub office I was called January
2025 so this is the first uh of our
office hours calls we've talked about
for quite some time we wanted
to to do these calls um I'm in a meeting
here with Maria and Alexander who also
works on they'll go for GitHub um
they'll share that camera and we'll try
to like answer your questions have a
discussion on topics the agenda for the
meeting um is kind of I'll go through
very quickly what's new what we've done
uh over the last month I know that since
this is the first I should go through
what we've done for the last like X
years but that's going to be a long
meeting then um so we're just going to
take what's new for in the latest
release very quickly and then go on to
Q&A and and uh an open discussion on
various topics what on your
minds um so let's Dive Right into what's
new let me know if you can see the
agenda slide now somebody put the thumbs
up I
guess
yes nice thank you so in the latest
release we in the latest month we
released version
6.3 there were like four uh things in
that one besid some some fixes and stuff
like that the conditional settings
were now applied on uh we you can now
Define conditional settings on buil mode
as well um we have pre-processor symbols
something a number of Partners ask for
and then no more this built artifacts
I'll explain that in a second and then a
new versioning strategy also requested
by one of our partners so let's just
have a look look at um the very first
one here so if you look at the left hand
side uh you'll be able to see like um
the settings that it takes to do
conditional
settings conditional settings is
really um you you can make some settings
and the settings file is defined when
these conditions are are met and you can
do conditions on which workflow you can
do it on now build modes as well
um and and and various other topics uh
you can you can put the conditions on
and then some settings so what I've done
here is I've defined two two different
build modes the default and the next
major and then I've set conditional
settings on if the build mode is next
major then use these settings like
override what's in the uh settings file
normally looking at the actual build
you'll see that it now builds uh the
first project twice once say default and
one say next major and if you dive into
the next major build you'll see the Top
Line there it applies preprocessor
symbols next major which use in your Al
codes to um to make sure that that you
you're using the right code there
version number you can do whatever the
pre-processor symbol is really something
you define and you'll see the artifacts
down there SBC inside of something and
that also applies from the conditions
settings next one no more this buil
artifacts uh now the this buil something
we've had from the very beginning if you
had multiple projects you would we would
like create these this buil artifacts in
order to use them when building the next
project in order to have like
dependencies resolved from a
multiproject uh
repository uh these this build artifacts
lasted for like 20 hours and was only
used for for the build process and not
meant for uh public consumption or what
do you say um so and they were kind of
yeah annoying um then we also had
requests from partners that they wanted
us to generate uh artifacts from pull
requests from current uh workflows from
next major next minor workflows they
wanted us basically to leave the
artifacts within the build even though
uh um they weren't producing artifacts
for for for shipping uh but maybe for
people wanted to use pull request for
deploying to an environment so that they
could kind of test the bits before they
actually um approved the pull request uh
so what we did was we removed the this
buil artifacts and we always produce
normal artifacts in a in a build process
now so in a in a multiproject repository
you will now see the right hand side uh
where you have the the various projects
and the apps and the dependencies and
stuff like that and and and those can be
actually used whatever um you will have
different names of these
um of these artifacts based on which
workflow it is so from the cicd you will
have the project uh the the branch and
apps and the version number in the next
major you will have uh the next major
name in there as well and then
a date I think date time after that so
there'll be various names so you can you
can enumerate the artifacts and see that
uh that it's the right
ones new versioning strategy um normally
we've always said that major minor comes
from App Json build release comes from
uh Al go for GitHub now it's actually
major minor build if you use versioning
strategy 3 that comes
from uh your app Jason and then only the
revision number now becomes the Run
number um what what does this mean well
it actually works pretty well when you
do a release because there you have to
do a sare like three digits and here
you'll have the three digits from your
app Json to release and we'll only be
counting the very last of the four
digits when you actually uh make a new
build so you would name your your build
version
1.0.1 and then when you run the create
release you'd be able to say I'll add
like plus 0.1 and it would be 1.1.0 or
You' add like plus
0.0.1 and you'll add one to the to the
third digit so it's the same as uh the
normal versioning strategy just three
digits are now um are now determined by
ajason and the fourth digit is now the
Run number if you rerun a build like if
something fails and you reran then in
the old days you would have the fourth
digit be the Run attempt that no longer
applies if you rerun it's just the same
version number it's not going
to um add anything to that
one so with
that I think we will switch over to open
discussion and Q&A I don't know if
people can actually unmute themselves or
if they have to use the Q&A pane but
um let's yeah people need to use the Q&A
pain let's see if we have
any any questions there not a single one
in my list maybe I'm in the wrong
location and somebody say hello or
create a post or whatever in the Q&A
pane so that we can see that we are that
it actually is working
maybe nobody could hear what I'm saying
and I've just been talking for
like 10
minutes
okay we do have
questions to says hi hi
to
okay oh we have a question in the chat
though we have a question what's new in
regards to
Performance getting a faster check if
the build
compiles
um
so a few things um one of the things we
did I can't remember I think that was in
December um we did a change in the Run
pipeline inside
of um inside of the BC contain hel that
actually now if you if you said that you
want to use compiler folder
um and you use a container you'll
actually be compiling using the compiler
folder and you'll create the container
after all the compile is done now it
means that the entire build will get a
little slower but it means that the
compile will be faster there's also
other ways of handling this so you can
you could imagine that you would uh have
multiple projects where you have the
tests in a separate project and actually
just build the various projects first
and then run the tests in a in a
separate project um we do have a an item
in our backlog to document these various
ways of setting up Alo to get best
performance or best matching whatever
people needs and and it might be that we
should
like up the priority of of these
documentations in order to make sure
that we can that you can do that but but
if you want like I think a good
mechanism would be to like structure
your repository so that you have the
only place you need the the container
really is in when you were running the
tests so you could build using compiler
folder in like in your projects that
contain the source code and the tests
really and then you could run the tests
in a separate project
[Music]
um
yeah see if we have other questions in
post yes
Todd asks about actions what does the
use workflow from branch do does it mean
the workflow runs on the context of that
Branch for all source and
configuration this is the GitHub one
this yes so that's the
top um yeah not radio button it's a top
drop down it means that the the code in
the workflow is from that and I
I'm I think we also honor that so we'll
use that Branch as our the branch for
which we are like taking the source and
stuff like that uh now be aware that if
you have a an Old Branch then you will
actually be running the action on the
old version of algo if you're running in
in that one now Maria is working on a on
a PR where we can like up update algo
system files in multiple branches so if
you're using multiple branches you'd be
able to um to keep them all to the same
version of Elo because if you pick this
one and you have a very old Branch You'
be running old code that might not work
anymore um but yes you'll be running in
the context of that Branch for source
and configuration and settings files and
everything we' be reading that from
there
I think you need to get it from top to
bottom because there was a previous
question from Thomas okay let's see I
can I can can you can you do this is
there possibility to automatically run
publish to environment we'd like to
update production environments outside
of working
hours uh yeah it's actually a question
we've had from quite some some people
right now you cannot do a sketch on that
because um it requires some input um
there is a mechanism to do that by
creating a small yo file that actually
spawns the publish to environment and
you can put a schedule in that one that
requires you to to create a small yam
file um I can if you I think I already
have a GitHub suggestion on this one um
but I should create document for how to
do that as well I'll take some notes
here
um so yeah publish to environment on a
schedule
schedule we'll take a note that we'll
create a documentation on how to do that
inside of Alo um within the next week or
two um I promise if I haven't done that
raise an issue on get up and say you
promised and I'll I'll make that
happen
and
thoughts
yes is there a possibility to deploy
only apps that really changed imagine
project with a lot of apps only the ones
changed deployment deploys all apps
floran you're right that is how it works
right now there is an PR called
incremental builds that
one will only build the the apps that
are changed or uh depends on apps that
are changed so if you if you modify the
the the very lowlevel app you'll still
rebuild all apps and actually deploy all
apps but if you are if you are just
modifying one app it will only rebuild
that one app and then the version number
of of all the other apps in the
repository will be the same and then it
will only deploy the modified or rebuilt
apps it's not really so we heard this
actually we had a round table directions
inia where where some of our partners
mentioned the same thing deployment
takes a lot of time building does not
necessarily take a lot of time but
deployment does so if we can just build
the apps that are really changed then
deployment would take over and figure
out oh that app is already installed so
not don't bother with that one and and
that's uh the pr that is open we're
expecting that one to get in uh preview
within the next few uh
weeks mik asks have you planned to spend
one of these office hour slots to do an
introduction to Alo for GitHub for
partners that are new to go for GitHub
or are in the process of deciding what
devops tools to use in their
organization
um we haven't
like I think the office hours is
typically for people who are yeah people
new people can listen in but but it's
typically for people to answer the
questions that that people have when
they're trying or they're they're
working with this
um we could do another office hours
calls for people that are new to go for
GitHub like really a directions session
or whatever we will be at directions as
well both in North America Andia and
maybe also in Asia this year and we'll
do like getting started we had a very
good getting started session last year
where where I I taught yonas blun how to
use ELO forget Hub on stage and that
worked pretty well um we could do stuff
like that I think in a in a session um
in the off sou session I also the launch
event sessions yeah the launch that se
is that getting started I think really
what's new there's
also an old one then the last last year
there's only a getting what's new I
remember there was also like getting
started as well yeah but um point taken
Eng and we'll uh we look at that
recently found out that there are
already many algo usage examples on
GitHub in the form of repositories is
there a list with a short explanation of
individual use
cases that would be a good idea to have
um I don't have a list per se um I I I
did start like let me roll back to the
the first slide here I did start a repo
here called GitHub business Central apps
algo office hours 202- one this
repository contains all the
samples where I took the screenshots in
this office hour course and I'll use the
same naming for one but maybe we should
have like um a list there is actually if
you go aka. msbc samples you will find
some samples apps but but they are kind
of yeah a little larger it's the big
Maps app and there's a few other uh with
the Power Platform integration and
there's the onboarding one from from
CERN um but maybe we should have yeah
probably use more of repositories in the
usage documentation and actually keep
these repositories and keep them alive
instead of just having them uh
shortlived and not maintain them it's a
good idea point taken glan we'll look at
that as well
and does a new change have page
scripting tasks for the results using
Alo for GitHub or Asher
pipelines this new
change uh so Manish so Sebastian is
actually here as well she has joined
and he is working on a results viewer
for Alo for GitHub we we
don't uh focus on Asha pipelines in this
team um but we are working on a results
viewer for p scripting tasks we're also
working on figuring out if we can run
the P scripting tasks as part of
deployment so when you're deploying to a
QA environment you could Define that you
would like to run the pig scripting
tasks in that environment as well so
that you can kind of see with your
customer data
or your test data or whatever that your
P scripting tasks actually completes
that
one but um I'll expect the results
viewer to be done before we ship version
seven in April isn't that a good yeah
definitely I don't know if we're going
to make it with the with the page
scripting test and QA
the primary problem there I think is
that the current page
scripting um Runner doesn't work with
MFA and a lot of people have and or must
enable NFA MFA for their authorization
or auth indication actually um so that
one requires
some some investigation
what is the recommended way to download
external dependencies like Contin
currently we have it on a server and
manually have to maintain
it
so the recommended way is to use net I
don't know if continia has a Nate feed I
don't think uh we have been
specifying in a good way how to how
Partners should do this and that Al go
for GitHub does support nuget both like
as
a as a provider and as a consumer of nou
packages so so if you trusted a nou feed
from continia then You' be able to have
automatic dependency resolution through
that one right now we do automatically
trust the the symbols feed from
appsource so the appsource symbols
should be uh updated but you can only
you can only compile the app so you
wouldn't be able to run tests in a
container with with those things
so um but I think nugat is is the answer
to this problem um and and we will be
looking into that as we've been looking
into that for a long time and it's
probably been yeah too long time
alping actually continue to ask if they
have a n feeds just to know um where
they are and and what they
do any news regarding the future of
local devv creation of development
containers features like installing
packages
from private repositories external
dependencies and stuff like that new get
feed GI packages are not
supported yeah so when running the local
DD you need your GitHub user need to
have permissions to read everything that
you can install in that
container
um if you don't have permissions to that
then we cannot get to that now U no real
way around that at this time
um yeah I don't know if if there's any
way to fix this right now local debv
builds the entire thing and publishes
things through a container I've been
thinking about whether it should not do
that whether it should take the latest
good build from GitHub and actually
download the binaries and just install
them and then you have something that is
running and and that you now have the
source maybe newer Source than what's
installed but you still have have um
easier access to all these dependencies
because they would be in GitHub uh
artifacts as apps test apps and
dependencies especially with the latest
fix if you go into a branch now you'd
actually have these as well so um maybe
we should start discussion on that on
GitHub ELO and and see if if that would
be
something uh
would be good to to do
yeah so Philip you uh as the same
question we had that as one of the first
questions we uh I'll I'll make a
documentation on how to do that it's not
something can you read the question oh
the question yeah it seems like cron
schedules are aborted on cicd runs BYO
are there any plans for making it
possible to schedule deployment publish
to environment in a similar fashion um
and yes we've heard that from a number
of partners and and we will document how
to do that that as things are today um
and
and in a in a later fashion like going
maybe a year or two from now U we are
talking about not actually so so
publishing to an environment is pushing
from your from your GitHub repo into an
environment what what we're talking
about the future should look like is
you're publishing to a to nou get feed
and you're actually installing from the
environment so you define on the
environment when you want to install the
update or when you want to uh to to take
the update from net and that's something
we are looking into whether that would
be a good way of solving that but um
right now publ to environment is uh yeah
the only way you can do that and and the
way to autate that is to create a small
file next to to that uh one and and find
what you want to to do there I'll I'll
create a small documentation sample on
how to do that and and add that and I
think I promised do that within the next
two weeks so expect that to be done
there I miss anyone
you can now archive the questions
but so floran added a comment to his
questions about the get packages in N uh
actually if what you
right now if you use the setting called
generate dependency
artifacts uh then in the buildt
artifacts there will be a a an artifact
called um project
branch dependencies and then version
number and and all the dependencies used
for the builds would be in that one so
so that would be possible um but it's
not something that local Deb look at at
this time that is what I talked about
something we could do in the future
instead of building actually just taking
things from the repo and or from the
latest good build and grabbing that to
um to create with
any more
questions comments
while people are writing their questions
these office hours calls we're going to
do them monthly uh this year except for
July and
December reason for not doing them in
December is obviously that we'll put
them on the last Tuesday in the month
and it's a bad date in December I think
so and we'll um alternate between a
morning time and an afternoon time here
in Copenhagen so we give us people a
chance to attend and also people
from from the Asia Pacific so
other questions maybe I should ask
questions but I don't know if I can get
an answer I saw that people can give
thumbs up on things but
um how many people or try to like find
the thumbs up thingy and uh if you are
if you're working on implementing Alo
then uh press the thumbs up button and
let see how many people on the call
would be doing
that one
two like a 10ish 11 12 people out of the
the the people on the call around that
probably
yeah and I guess that the remaining
people would then
be actual users of
Alo wouldn't make sense to join an
office call and not have a clue about
what they going
on so instead of if you don't have a
question you can type into the uh the
chat what has your uh what has the
biggest challenge been for for
implementing and go what are you like
what are you running into what you like
us to document better or or do better
for you as
St is there a possibility to run oh
there's another question here so is
there a possibility to run all workflows
on a self-hosted runner and not just the
builds
without editing the yam files yes there
is
Thomas there are two settings that
determines uh which Runners you use
there's the GitHub Runner which
determines what uh what Runners are
being used for the build jobs and then
there's the runs on that determines what
workflow what what Runners are being
used for all the other ones so if you
said runs Dash on to selfhosted or the
name of your self hosted Runners and run
the update Alo system files uh we will
set the
um the runs on in all the yaml files to
be yourself Runner except for the update
ELO system files the update ELO system
files will always use the GitHub hosted
Runner and the reason for that is that
if your self-hosted Runner is for some
reason no longer working or crashed or
whatever then you cannot change the
self-hosted runners because you do that
using the update ELO system files
meaning that that one needs to be um an
get posted Runner now I'm sure that
update ELO assistant files is not the
workflow that is going to take all of
your GitHub free minutes so I think that
one would be fine to have as a g posted
Runner
you do like
this I think that is a
link to see the documentation for
Ronan to comment
here makes sense what about the runner
groups is that a possibility yeah so
what you specify in runson or GitHub
Runner is exactly what's being used in
runson so if you use Runner group name
there or or tax in the runner uh that
same thing so yeah
so floran says follow up to Thomas's
question our self hosted rner is quite
fast but are there any recommendation
regarding the setup the server Hardware
softare
Etc so we will
always you guys can ch in if you want I
think our goal is to be as efficient as
possible on the GitHub of the runners
meaning that if you need to like see
what you need to install look at that
um we'll find the url for that one and
and post in the chat um the software
that is installed there you don't need
all the software uh we could actually
probably do a good do a list of what
what we need instead of like there's no
reason for them to install everything
thing that is on
posted so let's write down that
we'll if we don't have it we'll create a
list
of the software needed for that one and
as to memory it really depends on the
size of your app um some cases very
large apps will in order to be published
into a into a container actually use
quite a bit of memory um and and some of
the GitHub hosted Runners might not
be big enough for that but you can have
large Runners you have self-hosted
Runners that have more memories
so but uh we'll create
a some
documentation that
describes the um what needs to
be a little list of some software I'll
share that in the question okay like net
for example and
get
app things it might not be
complete take a note that we need to
make sure that that list is complete so
we can share
that
um we going what I'm missing trying to
implement go for GitHub in an
organization
is that it often looked as a developer
tool instead of a tool to maintain a
well Ro running BC
implementation so like more
documentation on management level that
will explain the total value of the
devop processes support by the go for
GitHub
okay wise words there it
we take a note of that
thank you for
sharing um I'm sure that like over time
that's also something that's going to
help us
uh yeah convince people that doing
everything yourself is not necessarily
the most efficient way or the most
economic way um going
forward so
is there a possibility to deploy some
test data to Containers during pipeline
run posting groups
Etc yeah so you can have um what they
called configuration
packages and remember the actual setting
of that there's a setting called
something you can Define I think it's
configuration
packages actually um where you can
Define which configuration packages are
applied doing
build um will find the link to the
documentation for that one and you can
apply that even per localization so you
can have a different configuration
package if you're running the tests for
us version for Danish version and for
Italy version you can have three
different config packages for
those um confli packages
is we also have an override called
import test data NPC container so if you
had a script called that then you can
also do whatever custom thing you need
to do for for configuration packages and
demo data whatever yeah if you like to
do things in code you can do
that there's one question in the chat as
well
it's been posted
there yeah we go to chat and second with
the new
resources function work in the do app as
well to can you ask that as a separate
question I'm not sure that I understand
that one um but
let's look in the chat if I need to sign
the buildt app using another CA Vault
not AC
keyb do I need to write My Signing
script if so should I include installing
navs or other prere
so what we utilize for for this is net
sign um for doing the signing and and if
if doet sign can sign your app using
whatever where you have your your your
certificate that would uh be our I mean
that we would recommend that we would
not recommend you to write your own code
and and maintain that and and other
things if you find that net sign can do
what you need but you need like to add
another um setting or whatever to to to
support other CA vaults as well uh
please work with us and we might be able
to actually include that in Alo so that
our signing mechanism could could could
work with that uh if it's not too big a
a of a change so yeah feel free to
create a PR on on on our uh repository
and we'll work with you to figure out
whether that's possible or
not for al42 we can include resources in
the app itself for a test app we could
use the resource in the initialization
step of the test it would be just a
different means of loading some
configuration data yeah so I think you
on to something here Todd
um and actually configuration packages
are if we are looking into the future
going away so we're not we right now
we're shipping conflict packages we had
a a few weeks where we did not um uh but
we are reshipping them but we know
they'll be going away so we be
deprecating the conflict packages as
part of the of the of the DVD or part of
our artifacts we're not dicating the
functionality of config packages we
still maintain that but we're not going
to ship our extended demo data as contct
packages we're going to ship that as
absence that kind of like what to is
referring to here like having an app
that would actually encode create the
demo data and and that's what we're
going to ship as well so in the future
we'll replace the the shipped config
packages with um demo data apps uh and
and yes that would be a good way of
doing that yourself as well to not have
a dependency of
some demo data that is in a conflict
package somewhere that will go away in
the future um and I expect I haven't
tried working with the resources in the
app but I strongly assume that you could
use that for that
purposes there was one question
before Oh
regarding the Telemetry data from
Alo quite a lot is recorded and we can
already evaluate various things for
ourselves especially PRS are there
already some kql queries from you you
can
provide or that you use yourself to
analyze usage on
errors some want to take that one yeah
uh we don't have that available but I
think it's a good idea uh uh I it's a
very like relatively new like module in
Alo but I think that is something we can
work on adding I think that would
benefit more people maybe even like a
dashboard or something we can share yeah
probably a dashboard that people could
see
there yeah good idea and then make if
we're missing something into limet we
can add it so that the dashboard
becomes more live maybe we can do a
actually even put the dashboard inside
of the repo so that
it's open source as well be
nice follow
up so the old sign tool of the SDK
wouldn't work I guess it would I mean I
don't I
haven't if if you use the old sign tool
you definitely have to like download the
um the
navip library yourself and and install
that and all of these things that that
happens automatically with net sign um
but yes you could go through sign tool
and stuff like that if you do that then
we would not take that as a um as a PR
to algo we've decided on net sign and
we'll
until until further proof prove that
that's the wrong way we'll stick to that
I mean we think that that is the right
choice and please uh put your questions
in the Q&A tab instead of in the chat uh
that helps a lot to get everything in
one location and we can collect that
afterwards
so my Q&A pain is now
stuck there's nothing
okay now I can scroll
again okay
and I said before thanks a lot for to to
in for sharing what he thinks it would
take for us to to make algo easier to
install or more digestible to
organizations if other people have
things we should like consider uh yeah
please speak up very much like to me
Floren dietr asks so we have the issue
that old pte are remaining published but
uninstalled in extensions list after
deployments gets a little
cluttered yeah
so I think I've seen that before in the
you have issues as well I don't think
there is an
unpublish mechanism in the um in the API
right now uh but but I can definitely
double check that so so they'll be
unpublished when you get the next major
or next minor update I think that is why
they get unpublished but
um can we
unpublishing
deployment to
enement um take that as an action
see if that's
possible to ask is a training available
somewhere for other developers and this
is hard to manage the training on my
own yeah the yearo workshop is Maria say
is probably the best starting place
um that one probably needs some some
love and attention as well but
we with
that one thing I learned is that the ELO
Workshop talks a lot about setting up AO
and and and and like importing your your
um your apps and stuff like that another
Workshop that we should do or we should
create somewhere uh is using Alo so now
you you have it set up and you have like
people who needs to work with GitHub and
algo on a daily basis what do they do
because they don't like they don't go to
GitHub and create a new repository and
stuff like that they'll be working with
it as as users more than as but that
probably yeah swings back to engus
comment about it's a developer tool more
than it's a it's a something that
management can can understand but also
yeah Consultants not probably got that
feedback as
well yeah using Workshop would be great
let's put that on our list of things to
document have three thumbs up in a
second so
sh
one of the challenges so uel asks one of
the challenges to push the customers to
migrate to go for from as devops is SSO
we have that in C
SSO uh single
signon single signon
um
well I do sign up so yeah um that's I
think an organizational level can be
forced at least it's forced for
Microsoft
organization and we need to sign in with
our Microsoft credentials and using the
Microsoft organization as that and use
MFA as we do with other all other uh
Microsoft
um resources so
so yes um I'm pretty sure you can set
that up on the organizational level and
and if your user belongs to that
organization you'll be forced to to do
that t says there still a future topics
in the AL go for GitHub Workshop are
they coming yeah well future topics is
for the future
and like we give rebates tomorrow is
what it says in the shop wall right no
yeah um definitely but it's something we
need to prioritize some more about the
documentation piece of this um they've
been lying around there for for too long
so um expect more uh over the next
months I'll I'll try to maybe schedule a
day every week where I'll do
documentation work instead of other
stuff that's probably the way to to do
this instead of waiting for like a a
chunk of time where you have time to
actually do these things uh probably
yeah set aside a day a week to to to
document is probably a good way
Emanuel says in that case how can we set
the connection to the keyword that now
use as a credential secret the
connection to the keyword the as a
credential secret uses a can be done in
a few ways so you can use what's called
Federated pretentions or you can use um
an a app that has access to the keyword
you typically don't use users for that
um so you still have the a credentials
in there in order to pinpoint the access
to the keyboard but not through a user
but through a aad app or using Federated
PRS said
may there's like seven minutes
left I think there is documentation I
Federate credential but yes I
will write that
down that we need that in the workshop
a term that has always confused me is
single project versus multi-project can
you
clarify um in the Alo context
so yeah so Alo
uh has a you can
have any number of AO repositories and
every repositor can have any number of
projects and every project can can have
any number of apps so an app is not a
project but an algo project is a
collection of apps that are typically
installed
together uh a repository is collecting
collection of projects that are
typically
released together so does that make
sense um the idea of the multi project
is that you can have
like um you can have
like a a W1 version of your app and then
you can have an Italy and a Danish
version of the app the reason for having
projects there is that the the Danish
version and the Italy version of your
app will compile with the Italy version
of of of business Central artifacts and
the Danish one with the Danish version
and the w11 with the worldwide version
of that obviously um and that would be
three different projects where DK and it
would would be have have a dependency on
the
w11 uh and that would uh then you build
W1 first and then the other countries
afterwards and you can then publish the
Italy one to an Italy organ environment
and so on and so
forth
now the the reason for having that is to
to because this is one app you have like
three different localizations of it it
belongs into one
repository sometimes you also have a
common or miscellaneous where you have
like an app is like licensing
functionality whatever you can put that
as a project in your repository but if
you have other repositor other apps it
might belong in a separate repository
and the recommendation is for for for
repositories in the same organization to
use GitHub packages as your um
dependency resolution for all the apps
that are in the same
organization um because that would be
like automated now if you if you have
like if you don't have very strict
borders between your apps and and like
your your changing things in in some of
the base apps together with in some of
the depending apps uh then you might put
them in one repository obviously and and
and that's that's totally fine as well
but our recommendation is to split them
so that a repository is what you release
uh and uh a project is what you install
and obviously if a project depends on
another project that would be installed
together with that project as
well
um if we make changes to the Italy
project is it possible to build only
that app while having two other projects
in the same
repository uh Emmanuel asks so today not
after we merge the incremental builds PR
that comes in preview in the next few
weeks uh it will it will be possible to
enable incremental builds and as such uh
only build the apps that are changed and
only deploy the apps that have changed
there as well
just take your
not Floren asks how is a script for
creation of local de andv behaving when
using a multiproject repository so the
local de andv is actually in the algo
folder which is in a project so you're
creating a development environment for
that project that you're working on uh I
do know that some people would like to
have a local de andv and working on all
projects at the same time that's not how
local Dean re works at the moment um but
I think yeah as before in this meeting
also we might we might have a look at
local D andd to see if we can make that
uh smarter better behaving than it does
today so let's
that Lo de old projects would be nice
yeah
so the problem is
that oh yeah you could do that so no no
sorry you obviously if you had a Danish
version and the Italy version you
wouldn't be able to create a container
for both those then you create two
containers obviously
right so you container kind of have to
be connected to one of the projects
because that one carries the artifacts
but you could load the other
um projects in yes code I guess yeah
we'll have to think about that one
for Emanuel asks do we need a license
When developing in a local environment
an appsource app you not need it for
developing that you need the license uh
you need the object range in order to
deploy to appsource um but the the
Kronos license that is included in the
artifacts is a perfectly good
development license and you don't need
to to have a local license file for that
sake but again yeah you need your object
range and you need to be registered as a
as a publisher with appsource in order
to develop and appsource
apps I think time's
up uh let's say is anything in the chat
same here here that's not started on the
AL go yet but need to understand the
possibilities we'll do our best Eric
to to do that and good to see you here
Eric it's been a
while but um yeah thanks a lot for for
joining everybody and
um looking forward to see many a few in
a month or in two months from now thank
you
thank you